https://www.tonydixonmusic.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
This is privacy notice of Tony Dixon Manufacturing Ltd.We respect your privacy and are determined to protect your personal data. The purpose of this privacynotice is to inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless ofwhere you visit it from). We’ll also tell you about your privacy rights and how the data protection lawprotects you.1. WHO WE ARE AND IMPORTANT INFORMATIONWhat is the purpose of this privacy notice?This privacy notice aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data throughyour use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you purchase aproduct or fill in the contact form.This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.You must read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specificoccasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of howand why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended tooverride them.Data controller(s)Tony Dixon Manufacturing Ltd is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referredto as Tony Dixon Manufacturing Ltd, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice). Our contact details are Unit4, Creative Court, Clovelly Road Industrial Estate, Clovelly Road, Bideford, EX39 3HN, 01237 422440,info@tonydixonmusic.co.uk www.tonydixonmusic.co.uk . For all data matters contact the above contactdetails.Third-party links outside of our controlThis website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links orenabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not controlthese third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements.When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.2. THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOUPersonal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that personcan be identified. You can find out more about personal data from the Information Commissioners Office.We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have groupedtogether follows Name, Address, Telephone number, email address in order for us to process your order :• Identity Data includes: First name, Last name, Title.• Contact Data includes Billing address, Delivery address, Email address, Telephone number.We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about yourrace or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade unionmembership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect anyinformation about criminal convictions and offences.If you fail to provide personal dataWhere we need to collect your personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you andyou fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or aretrying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we mayhave to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.3. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:Directly. You may give us your name and email address by filling in the contact form or by correspondingwith us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you Apply for ourproducts or services• Fill in our contact form• Purchase a product• Request information to be sent to you.4. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personaldata in the following circumstances:• Performance of Contract this means processing your data where it is necessary for the performanceof a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such acontract.• Legitimate Interest this means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our businessto enable us to give you the best service/product and the most secure experience. We make sure weconsider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights beforewe process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data foractivities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or areotherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting uson info@tonydixonmusic.co.uk• Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation this means processing your personal data where it isnecessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.[Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data as we do not sellyour information to a third party or market to you via your contact details.PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data,with the legal bases we rely on to do so.Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specificpurpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us info@tonydixonmusic.co.uk if you need detailsabout the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than oneground has been set out in the table below.Purpose To process your orderActivity (a) Identity(b) ContactType of data Lawful basis for processingincluding basis of legitimateinterestPerformance of a contract with youPurposeTo answer your enquiry via emailor the contact form on ourwebsiteActivity ContactType of data Lawful basis for processingincluding basis of legitimateinterestCustomer servicePurposeVAT purposesActivity (a) Identity(b) ContactType of data Lawful basis for processingincluding basis of legitimateinterestAdministrative purposesMarketingWe strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketingand advertising. We do not currently contact customers for marketing and advertising purposesThird-party marketingWe do not share your details with third party marketing.CookiesYou can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or accesscookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may becomeinaccessible or not function properly.Change of purpose We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it e.g. the completion of yourorder or enquiry, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason iscompatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for thenew purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact info@tonydixonmusic.co.ukIf we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain thelegal basis which allows us to do so.Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance withthe above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.5. WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITHWe may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in thetable in paragraph 4 above.External Third Parties Service• Providers based UK who provide IT and system administration services.• Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the UK whoprovide consultancy, Banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.• HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based in the UK who require reportingof processing activities in certain circumstances.• We use PayPal to process your transaction when ordering on our website. We do not control thesethird-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements.• Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets.Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to ourbusiness, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacynotice.We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance withthe law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposesand only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with ourinstructions.6. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERSWe do not transfer your personal data outside the European Econmic area (EEA)7. DATA SECURITYWe have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentallylost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to yourpersonal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need toknow. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty ofconfidentiality.We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you andany applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.8. DATA RETENTIONWe will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for,including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, andsensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of yourpersonal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve thosepurposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.By law we have to keep basic information about our customers including contact, identity and transactiondata for six years after they cease bring customers for TAX purposes. In some circumstances you can ask usto delete your data: see Your legal rights below for further information.In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated withyou) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely withoutfurther notice to you.9. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTSUnless subject to an exemption under the data protection laws, you have the following rights with respectto your personal data:• The right to request a copy of the personal data which we hold about you;• The right to request that we correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;• The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary to retain such data;• The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time, where consent was the lawful basisfor processing your data;• The right to request that we provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit thatdata directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), where applicable 9i.e.where our processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of our contract with youor where we process your data by automated means);• The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, torequest a restriction is placed on further processing;• The right to object to our processing of personal data, where applicable i.e. where processing is basedon our legitimate interests (or in performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of officialauthority); direct marketing or processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research andstatistics).If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email info@tonydixonmusic.co.ukNo fee required – with some exceptionsYou will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights).However, we may charge a reasonable admin fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive orexcessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.What we may need from youWe may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure yourright to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure toensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contactyou to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.Time limit to respondWe try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than amonth if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we willnotify you and keep you updated.10. CHANGES TO THIS NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGESThis privacy policy was last updated on 23rd May 2018. From 25th May 2018 there will be changes in Dataprotection laws and we will then be able to respond to some of your requests. We are still working towardsgetting our systems ready for some of these changes.Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. It is important thatthe personal data we hold about you is accurate and current.11. QUERIES, REQUESTS OR CONCERNSTo exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints in relation to this policy or any other data protectionmatter between you and us, please in the first instance contact Tony Dixon Manufacturing, Unit 4 Creativecourt, Bideford, Devon EX39 3HN.If this does not resolve your complaint to your satisfaction, you have the right to lodge a complaint with theInformation Commissioners Office on 03031231113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF,England, UK.
This is privacy notice of Tony Dixon Manufacturing Ltd.We respect your privacy and are determined to protect your personal data. The purpose of this privacynotice is to inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless ofwhere you visit it from). We’ll also tell you about your privacy rights and how the data protection lawprotects you.1. WHO WE ARE AND IMPORTANT INFORMATIONWhat is the purpose of this privacy notice?This privacy notice aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data throughyour use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you purchase aproduct or fill in the contact form.This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.You must read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specificoccasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of howand why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended tooverride them.Data controller(s)Tony Dixon Manufacturing Ltd is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referredto as Tony Dixon Manufacturing Ltd, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice). Our contact details are Unit4, Creative Court, Clovelly Road Industrial Estate, Clovelly Road, Bideford, EX39 3HN, 01237 422440,info@tonydixonmusic.co.uk www.tonydixonmusic.co.uk . For all data matters contact the above contactdetails.Third-party links outside of our controlThis website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links orenabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not controlthese third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements.When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.2. THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOUPersonal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that personcan be identified. You can find out more about personal data from the Information Commissioners Office.We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have groupedtogether follows Name, Address, Telephone number, email address in order for us to process your order :• Identity Data includes: First name, Last name, Title.• Contact Data includes Billing address, Delivery address, Email address, Telephone number.We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about yourrace or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade unionmembership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect anyinformation about criminal convictions and offences.If you fail to provide personal dataWhere we need to collect your personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you andyou fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or aretrying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we mayhave to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.3. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:Directly. You may give us your name and email address by filling in the contact form or by correspondingwith us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you Apply for ourproducts or services• Fill in our contact form• Purchase a product• Request information to be sent to you.4. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personaldata in the following circumstances:• Performance of Contract this means processing your data where it is necessary for the performanceof a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such acontract.• Legitimate Interest this means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our businessto enable us to give you the best service/product and the most secure experience. We make sure weconsider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights beforewe process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data foractivities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or areotherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting uson info@tonydixonmusic.co.uk• Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation this means processing your personal data where it isnecessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.[Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data as we do not sellyour information to a third party or market to you via your contact details.PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data,with the legal bases we rely on to do so.Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specificpurpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us info@tonydixonmusic.co.uk if you need detailsabout the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than oneground has been set out in the table below.Purpose To process your order Activity (a) Identity(b) ContactType of data Lawful basis for processingincluding basis of legitimateinterestPerformance of a contract with youPurpose To answer your enquiry via emailor the contact form on ourwebsiteActivity ContactType of data Lawful basis for processingincluding basis of legitimateinterestCustomer servicePurposeVAT purposesActivity(a) Identity(b) ContactType of data Lawful basis for processingincluding basis of legitimateinterestAdministrative purposesMarketingWe strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketingand advertising. We do not currently contact customers for marketing and advertising purposesThird-party marketingWe do not share your details with third party marketing.CookiesYou can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or accesscookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may becomeinaccessible or not function properly.Change of purpose We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it e.g. the completion of yourorder or enquiry, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason iscompatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for thenew purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact info@tonydixonmusic.co.ukIf we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain thelegal basis which allows us to do so.Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance withthe above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.5. WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITHWe may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in thetable in paragraph 4 above.External Third Parties Service• Providers based UK who provide IT and system administration services.• Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the UK whoprovide consultancy, Banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.• HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based in the UK who require reportingof processing activities in certain circumstances.• We use PayPal to process your transaction when ordering on our website. We do not control thesethird-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements.• Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets.Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to ourbusiness, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacynotice.We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance withthe law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposesand only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with ourinstructions.6. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERSWe do not transfer your personal data outside the European Econmic area (EEA)7. DATA SECURITYWe have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentallylost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to yourpersonal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need toknow. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty ofconfidentiality.We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you andany applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.8. DATA RETENTIONWe will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for,including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, andsensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of yourpersonal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve thosepurposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.By law we have to keep basic information about our customers including contact, identity and transactiondata for six years after they cease bring customers for TAX purposes. In some circumstances you can ask usto delete your data: see Your legal rights below for further information.In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated withyou) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely withoutfurther notice to you.9. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTSUnless subject to an exemption under the data protection laws, you have the following rights with respectto your personal data:• The right to request a copy of the personal data which we hold about you;• The right to request that we correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;• The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary to retain such data;• The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time, where consent was the lawful basisfor processing your data;• The right to request that we provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit thatdata directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), where applicable 9i.e.where our processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of our contract with youor where we process your data by automated means);• The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, torequest a restriction is placed on further processing;• The right to object to our processing of personal data, where applicable i.e. where processing is basedon our legitimate interests (or in performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of officialauthority); direct marketing or processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research andstatistics).If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please email info@tonydixonmusic.co.ukNo fee required – with some exceptionsYou will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights).However, we may charge a reasonable admin fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive orexcessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.What we may need from youWe may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure yourright to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure toensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contactyou to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.Time limit to respondWe try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than amonth if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we willnotify you and keep you updated.10. CHANGES TO THIS NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGESThis privacy policy was last updated on 23rd May 2018. From 25th May 2018 there will be changes in Dataprotection laws and we will then be able to respond to some of your requests. We are still working towardsgetting our systems ready for some of these changes.Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. It is important thatthe personal data we hold about you is accurate and current.11. QUERIES, REQUESTS OR CONCERNSTo exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints in relation to this policy or any other data protectionmatter between you and us, please in the first instance contact Tony Dixon Manufacturing, Unit 4 Creativecourt, Bideford, Devon EX39 3HN.If this does not resolve your complaint to your satisfaction, you have the right to lodge a complaint with theInformation Commissioners Office on 03031231113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF,England, UK.
HAND FINISHED WHISTLES
© Tony Dixon Music 2018
Privacy Policy
Cookie Policy
We're Open!
Thank you for your patience during these unusual times. We are now back up and running and look forward to receiving your orders!
